<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!-- QUESTIONS -->
    <string name="Q01">Two albatrosses just married and are now starting to build their new nest.\n\nThey have gathered 110 sticks and plan to use all of them.\nThey divide the sticks in two parts, so that the husband, a faster worker, will have a part that\'s 150 percent of that of his wife.\n\nHow many sticks the female albatross will have?</string>
    <string name="Q02">Joe and Jack are math-lovers.\nOn a beautiful morning, Joe asks Jack: "My friend, what is the biggest number you can write with only 2 digits?"\n\nJack think about it for a while, and then gives the correct answer.\nWhat did he said?</string>
    <string name="Q03">A man saw a beautiful woman enter a ballroom.\nHe wanted to follow her and invite her for a dance, but the club was very exclusive: only member knowing the secret password could enter. He did not know the password, but the woman was so beautiful he decided to wait by the door and listen what others said.\n\nA club member knocked on the door and the doorman said "twelve". The member replied "six" and was let in. A second member came to the door and the doorman said "six". The member replied "three" and was let in.\n\nThe man thought he had heard enough and walked up to the door.\nThe doorman said "ten" and the man replied "five". but he was not let in.\n\nWhat should have he said?</string>
    <string name="Q04">A small boat is sailing on a river going upstream.\nDuring the day, the sailors manage to take it 3 Km forth, but during the night, while they sleep, the current takes the boat 2 Km back.\nThe river is 30 Km Long.\n\nHow many days does it take them to get to complete their journey?</string>
    <string name="Q05">How many animals of each species did Moses bring aboard the Ark?</string>
    <string name="Q06">The flowers growing on the hill double the area they cover every 36 hours.\n\nSeventy days ago, there was only a single flower on the hill, but now it is completely covered with flowers. How many days did it take to cover a quarter of the hill?</string>
    <string name="Q07">Because cigars cannot be entirely smoked, a poor girl who likes smoking but cannot afford to buy cigars, collects cigar butts.\nShe can make a cigar out of every 5 butts that she finds.\n\nToday, he has collected 50 cigar butts: how many cigars will he be able to smoke?</string>
    <string name="Q08">A man built his house exactly on the north pole.\n\nOne day he goes hunting, and bringing his compass along. He walks 10 miles south, then 10 miles east, then 10 mile north and finally stops to rest.\n\nHow many miles is he far from home?</string>
    <string name="Q09">As I was traveling to St. Ives,\nI met a man with seven wives.\nEach wife of his had seven cats,\nand each day they caught seven rats.\n\nHow many were traveling to St. Ives?</string>
    <string name="Q10">A bus driver was heading down the street.\n\nHe went past a stop sign without stopping, he turned left where there was a "no left turn" sign and he went the wrong way on a one-way street.\nThen he went on the left side of the road past a cop car.\n\nBut he did not break any law.\nWhy not?</string>
    <string name="Q11">What is once in a minute, twice in a moment, and never in a thousand years?</string>
    <string name="Q12">Four kids carry a basket with four apples in it.\nWhen it is time for a snack, each kid takes an apple, yet one apple remains in the basket.\n\nHow is this possible?</string>
    <string name="Q13">Joe wants to send a valuable object to a friend.\nHe has a box which is more than large enough to contain the object and he also has several locks with keys.\n\nThe box has a locking ring which is more than large enough to have a lock attached, but Joe\'s friend does not have the key to any of the locks.\n\nHow could Joe send the object securely?\n\n(Note: he cannot send a key in an unlocked box, since it might be copied)</string>
    <string name="Q14">Four girls, Ann, Betty, Carla and Diana, had a race on the beach.\n\nSeen that:\nBetty was as many places behind Carla as Diana was ahead of Ann.\nCarla was not first and Ann was not second.\n\nWho won the race?</string>
    <string name="Q15">If you divide sixty by ½, then add ¼ of the result, then decrease the resulting number by its 10 percent, what would you have?</string>
    <string name="Q16">Some bees are hovering over some flowers.\nWe know that:\n\n1) If each bee lands on a flower, one bee won\'t get a flower.\n2) If two bees share each flower, there will be one flower left out.\n\nHow many flowers and bees are there?</string>
    <string name="Q17">Only one of these statements is true:\n\n1) I have 5 or more cats\n2) I have less than 5 cats\n3) I have at least 1 cat\n\nHow many cats do I have?</string>
    <string name="Q18">In a family, each of the boys has the same number of brothers as he has of sisters, while each of the girls has twice as many brothers as she has sisters.\n\nHow many boys and girls are there in this family?</string>
    <string name="Q19">Once upon a time there was a beautiful princess named Anna.\n\nThe King wanted to be sure his daughter married an intelligent man, so, to test his daughter\'s suitors, he hid Anna\'s picture in one of three boxes.\n\nOn the gold box was the message \'Anna\'s picture is in this box\'.\nThe silver box had the message \'Anna\'s picture is not in this box.\'\n\'Anna\'s picture is not in the gold box\', was written on the bronze one.\n\nThe King would tell each suitor \'Only one of the three messages is correct.\'\n\nWhich box contained Anna\'s picture?</string>
    <string name="Q20">A certain number has three digits.\n\nThe sum of the three digits is 1/36 of this number.\nSeven times the left digit plus 9 is equal to 5 times the sum of the two other digits.\n8 times the second digit minus 9 is equal to the sum of the first and third.\n\nWhat is the number?</string>
    <string name="Q21">I am four times as old as my daughter, and in 20 years time I shall be twice as old as her.\n\nHow old are we now?</string>
    <string name="Q22">A farmer wants to plant his seeds in a sqared area.\n\nHe made a first attempt and found that he had 39 seeds left over.\nHe then started increasing the number of seeds on a side by one, but found that 50 additional seeds were needed to complete the new square.\n\nHow many seeds did the farmer have?</string>
    <string name="Q23">\'The following sentence is false.\'\n\'The preceding sentence is true.\'\n\nAre these sentences true or false?</string>
    <string name="Q24">Mary was working in a chemistry lab with a mixture of chemicals that was 90% water and weighed 20 pounds.\nAfter returning to the lab from a weekend break, she calculated the mixture was now 50% water.\n\nHow much does the mixture now weigh?\n\n(Assume the non-water part of the mixture was not affected by evaporation)</string>
    <string name="Q25">Einstein wrote this quiz last century and he said that 98 percent of the people in the world would not be able to solve the quiz.\n\nThere are 5 houses in 5 different colors, and in each house lives a person with a different nationality.\nThese 5 owners drink a certain type of beverage, smoke a certain brand of cigar, and keep a certain pet. No owners have the same pet, smoke the same brand of cigar or drink the same drink.\nWho owns the fish?\n\nKnow that:\nThe Brit lives in a red house.\nThe Swede keeps dogs as pets.\nThe Dane drinks tea.\nThe green house is on the left of the white house.\nThe green house owner drinks coffee.\nThe person who smokes Pall Mall rears birds.\nThe owner of the yellow house smokes Dunhill.\nThe man living in the house right in the middle drinks milk.\nThe Norwegian lives in the first house.\nThe man who smokes Blend lives next door to the one who keeps cats.\nThe man who keeps horses lives next door to the man who smokes Dunhill.\nThe owner who smokes Blue Master drinks beer.\nThe German smokes Prince.\nThe Norwegian lives next to the blue house.\nThe man who smokes Blend has a neighbor who drinks water.\n\nWith these 15 clues the problem is solvable.</string>
    <string name="Q26">A poor man tells a rich man\'I know all the songs known to man.\'\n\nThe rich man laughed and said, \'I bet all the money in my pocket that you can\'t sing a song with my daughter\'s name in it: Sarah Lee Greyson.\'\n\nThe poor man went home rich and the rich man went home poor.\nWhat song did the man sing?</string>
    <string name="Q27">Last night I had a nightmare.\nI was locked in a room with only two doors: one had a cannibal orc behind it, the other was boiling, because it had loads of magnifying glasses with blazing sun.\n\nIt was a difficult situation, but I managed to escape.\nHow??</string>
    <string name="Q28">A man takes a 2-mile walk while it is raining, but when he goes back home there is not a single drop of water on his hair.\n\nHow is it possible?</string>
    <string name="Q29">A Russian spy wants to kill James Bond.\nShe offers him a cup of poisoned punch and ice and Bond instantly drinks it, but he doesn\'t die.\n\nThe Russian spy is very frustrated and realizes that she made a mistake preparing the poison.\nWhat was her mistake?</string>
    <string name="Q30">A bridge is forty miles long and it can only hold 1250 lbs.\n\nA truck weighing exactly 1250 lbs crosses the bridge.\n\nAs it reaches the middle, a bird weighing 2 lbs lands on it, but despite the added weight, the bridge did not collapse.\n\nWhy?</string>
    <string name="Q31">Two sailors are standing on opposite sides of the ship.\nOne is looking west and the other east and, at the same time, they can see each other clearly.\n\nHow is it possible?</string>
    <string name="Q32">A man enters a bar and asks for a glass of water.\n\nThe man behind the counter pulls out a gun and points it in the other\'s face.The first man than thanks and leaves.\n\nWhat happened?</string>
    <string name="Q33">There is a low railroad bridge in the town of Eversun, and a truck driver is standing in front of it, very sad.\n\n\'This is the shortest road for my destination, but my truck is just an inch higher than the indicated height of the opening. I will be late for the delivery!\'\n\nFortunately, a kind and clever man that is passing by notices the driver\'s sadness and suggests a solution to his problem.\n\nWhat did he suggest?</string>
    <string name="Q34">Four kids were playing, and one of them threw a ball right through my window.\n\nHere\'s what they had to say:\nAlfred:It was not me, I didn\'t break a thing\nBen: Ok, it was me, I broke it\nCarl: Don\'t be mad at Alfred: he didn\'t do anything\nDavid: Ben didn\'t break the glass, I swear\n\nSomeone must be lying, but how many of them are telling the truth?\nAnd who smashed my window?</string>
    <string name="Q35">How many seconds are there in a year?</string>
    <string name="Q36">Bertha killed dozens of people.\nEverybody knows she\'s responsible for their death, but she was never put in jail.\n\nWhy?</string>
    <string name="Q37">Is it possible for two twins to have birthdates different for day, moth and year?</string>
    <string name="Q38">What is it that ends everything, always?</string>
    <string name="Q39">Jackie\'s mom has 12 kids: January, February, March, April, May, June, July, August, September, October, November and…\n\nWhat is the 12th child?</string>
    <string name="Q40">An explorer discovers the mummy of a man perfectly preserved.\n\nAfter studying it for a few moments, the explorer comes to the conclusion that the mummy is that of Adam: the first man that God created.\n\nHow could he guess that?</string>
    <string name="Q41">Jane changed her telephone number and needs to communicate her friends the new one.\nShe has ten friends and want the info to be spread in the shortest time possible.\nIf everyone cooperates, and the number takes one minute to be told and memorized, what is the shortest time possible to spread the new number through all Jane\'s friends?</string>
    <string name="Q42">On a tree a target is painted, an arrow has been shot perfectly in the middle of it.\n\nThe archer who shot the arrow is not a very good one though, but when he gets asked \'Is it you, who shot this arrow\' he answers yes and he is telling the truth.\n\nHow is it possible?</string>
    <string name="Q43">Two wooden sticks burn completely in 1 hour.\nThey are of uneven density, so they don\'t burn at the same speed, but completely burn in an hour.\n\nYou have a match box to light the sticks and want to use them to measure 30 minutes: how could you do?\nAnd what would you do if you wanted to measure 45 minutes instead?</string>
    <string name="Q44">A doctor has 3 patients and 24 oz of the medicine they need.\nEach patient needs exactly 8oz of that medicine to be healed, but the doctor only has three cups that can contain 5, 11 and 13 oz.\nEach cup can only go to a single patient.\n\nHow can the doctor heal all his three patients?</string>
    <string name="Q45">How can you throw a ball as hard as you can and have it come back to you, even if it doesn\'t hit anything, there is nothing attached to it, and no one else catches or throws it back?</string>
    <string name="Q46">2 mothers and 2 daughters walk into a store.\nThey buy 3 dresses, so that each person has now a new dress.\n\nHow is this possible?</string>
    <string name="Q47">Three guys are trying to get across a river on a boat that can only hold 400 pounds.\n\nTwo guys weigh 200 pounds each, while the other guy weighs 400 pounds.\n\nHow do they manage to get all three across the river?</string>
    <string name="Q48">There is a place where things don\'t always follow the rules we know.\n\nIn this place where, for example, yesterday always come after tomorrow.\n\nWhat place is this?</string>
    <string name="Q49">A donkey is sleeping, tied to a 6 meter rope.\nWhen it wakes up it is very hungry.\n\n7 meters away from where it was sleeping, there is a pile of hay, so the donkey gets to its feet and easily get to eat the hay.\n\nHow is this possible?</string>
    <string name="Q50">Seen that:\n\n5+3+2 = 151022\n9+2+4 = 183652\n8+6+3 = 482466\n5+4+5 = 202541\n\nThen 7+2+5 = ?</string>
    <string name="Q51">How did Mark legally marry three women in Michigan, without divorcing any of them, becoming legally separated, or any of them dying?</string>
    <string name="Q52">Only one of these ten statements is true. Can you find it?\n\n1) One of these 10 statements is false\n2) Two of these 10 statements are false\n3) Three of these 10 statements are false\n4) Four of these 10 statements are false\n5) Five of these 10 statements are false\n6) Six of these 10 statements are false\n7) Seven of these 10 statements are false\n8) Eight of these 10 statements are false\n9) Nine of these 10 statements are false\n10)  All of these statements are false</string>
    <string name="Q53">How can you measure the shortest to be longer than the longest?</string>
    <string name="Q54">In a race and you just passed the third runner.\nWhat place are you now?</string>
    <string name="Q55">You have 8 weights and a scale, and you can use the scale only twice.\nThe weights are all identical save one, that is lighter.\n\nHow do you find the lightest weight?</string>
    <string name="Q56">Brandon is driving next to Central Park to party with his friends for his fourth birthday.\n\nHow is this possible?</string>
    <string name="Q57">Mr. and Mrs. Hibbert have 5 daughters, and each daughter has a brother.\nHow many brothers do the 5 girls have?</string>
    <string name="Q58">Before Mount Everest was discovered, what was the highest mountain in the world?</string>
    <string name="Q59">This morning Brian\'s girlfriend sent him a tweet reading:\n\n\'A,B,C,D,E,F,G,H,I,J,K,L,M,N,O,P,Q,R,S,T,V,W,X,Y,Z\'.\n\nWhat did she mean?</string>
    <string name="Q60">Mike challenges Jack to a game of chess.\nJack claims he\'s never lost before, yet Mike somehow beat him easily.\n\nHow did he do?</string>
    <string name="Q61">1\n11\n21\n1211\n111221\n\nWhat\'s next?</string>
    <string name="Q62">Two people were walking in opposite directions.\nBoth of them walked 6 miles forward then took right and walked 8 miles.\n\nHow far is each from starting positions?</string>
    <string name="Q63">The big donkey is the father of the small donkey, but the small donkey is not the son of the big donkey.\nHow is this possible?</string>
    <string name="Q64">A farmer has certain number of cows and birds.\nThey have 172 eyes and 344 legs.\n\nHow many cows and birds does he have?</string>
    <string name="Q65">Albert has 14 red socks and 14 white socks in a drawer.\nHe dresses up in total darkness because he doesn\'t want to wave his wife.\n\nWhat is the minimum number of socks that he should take to be sure to get a correct pair?</string>
    <string name="Q66">There is a number that, when it is multiplied by 13, it becomes greater to 105 by an amount with which it is lesser to 105 by now.\n\nWhat is the number?</string>
    <string name="Q67">A fast truck leaves London for Brighton and at the same time a slow truck leaves Brighton for London.\n\nThe fast truck travels at 80 mph and the slow truck travels at 35 mph.\n\nWhen they meet, which is farther from London?</string>
    <string name="Q68">A girl, a boy, and a dog start walking down a road.\nThey start at the same time, from the same point, in the same direction.\n\nThe dog runs from boy to girl and back again with a constant speed of 10 km/h, the boy walks at 5 km/h and the girl at 6 km/h.\n\nHow far does the dog travel in 1 hour?</string>
    <string name="Q69">A pool has four taps.\nThe first tap takes two days to fill the pool, the second tap three days, the third four days and the last one only 6 hours.\n\nHow long will it take to fill the pool using all 4 taps at once?</string>
    <string name="Q70">A lady jumped off a ten story building didn\'t die.\nHow could this happen?</string>
    <string name="Q71">During an exam a student asks the teacher how much time is left.\nThe teacher answers that the amount of time left is 1/5 of the time already spent.\n\nHow much time is left?</string>
    <string name="Q72">I have a donkey. Do you know what color it is?\n\nAlan said, \'I guess it is not black\'.\nBrian said, \'It is either brown, or gray\'.\nCharlie said \'I know it is brown\'.\n\nI said, \'At least one of you is right and at least one of you is wrong\'.\n\nCan you guess what is the color of my donkey, if the color is one of the above?</string>
    <string name="Q73">A lady and a gentleman are sister and brother.\nWe do not know who is older, but someone asked them.\n\nThe sister said: I am older. And the brother said: I am younger.\nWe know that at least one of them was lying.\nWho is older?</string>
    <string name="Q74">8 monkeys take 8 minutes to eat 8 bananas.\n\n1) How many minutes would it take 3 monkeys to eat 3 bananas?\n2) How many monkeys would it take to eat 48 bananas in 48 minutes?</string>
    <string name="Q75">Two people are traveling by bike at 10 miles/hour in opposite direction.\n\nWhen they are at a distance of 50 miles, a housefly lands on the first cyclist and then flies to the other at a speed of 16 miles/hour.\n\nWhat is the distance covered by the fly?</string>
    <string name="Q76">If all Zips are Zoodles, and all Zoodles are Zonkers, then all Zips are definitely Zonkers.\n\nIs this true?</string>
    <string name="Q77">Sue is both the 50th best and the 50th worst athlete of her school. How many students attend her school?</string>
    <string name="Q78">Ten people can dig 60 holes in 120 days.\nHow many days it takes five people dig 30 holes?</string>
    <string name="Q79">What number is a half\n of a quarter\n  of a tenth\n   of 800?</string>
    <string name="Q80">Take 2 apples from 3 apples.\nWhat do you have?</string>
    <string name="Q81">Suppose you drove a bus with 43 people on board from Chicago and stopped at Pittsburgh to pick up 7 more people.\nThen you drop off 5 passengers and at Cleveland and 8 passengers at the next stop, where you also pick up 4 people.\n\nWhat is the name of the driver?</string>
    <string name="Q82">Mary had a certain number of cookies.\nAfter eating one, she gave half the remnants to her sister.\nAfter eating another cookie, she gave half of what was left to her brother.\n\nMary has now only five cookies left: how many did she start with?</string>
    <string name="Q83">A spaceship received three messages in a strange language from a distant planet.\nThe astronauts studied these messages and found that:\n\n\'Vark Gombrouark Stuxien\' means \'Danger Rocket Explosion\'\n\'Edain Mnyatur Vark\' means \'Danger spaceship Fire\'\n\'Gombrouark Gimilzor Gondor\' means "Bad Gas Explosion\'.\n\nCan you guess what does \'Stuxien\' mean? </string>
    <string name="Q84">Can a man living in Spain be buried in Portugal?</string>
    <string name="Q85">Which one of the five is least like the other four?\n\nHORSE\nKANGAROO\nZEBRA\nDEER\nDONKEY</string>
    <string name="Q86">John wants to buy 9 large boxes of peaches at the store, but he can only carry 2 boxes at a time from the store to home\n\nHow many trips to the store does he have to make?</string>
    <string name="Q87">Which one of the numbers does not belong in the series?\n\n1\n2\n5\n10\n13\n26\n29\n48</string>
    <string name="Q88">What falls but never breaks?</string>
    <string name="Q89">Which one is the odd one out?\n\nURN\nURA\nARS\nRTH\nTER\nNUS</string>
    <string name="Q90">Hawthorne is to people\nas\nDoppler is to… ?</string>
    <string name="Q91">Some months have 31 days.\nHow many have 30?</string>
    <string name="Q92">Everyday a man leaves his 20th floor apartment via the elevator, but when he comes home he gets off at the 16th floor and walks up the rest of the floors.\n\nWhy?</string>
    <string name="Q93">You have two buckets: one is a 3 gallon bucket and the other is a 5 gallon bucket.\n\nYou must measure out 4 gallons using only these two buckets\n\nHow could you do?</string>
    <string name="Q94">What completes the series?\n\nABC - 6 - FGH - 336 - CCFCCGCCH - ?</string>
    <string name="Q95">The price of an article was cut 20 percent for a sale.\n\nBy what percent would the price need to be increased now, to sell the article at the original price?</string>
    <string name="Q96">An old man was fishing, when he got this strange fish.\n\nIt had a head 9 inches long.\nThe tail was equal to the size of the head plus one-half the size of the body.\nThe body was the size of the head plus the tail.\n\nHow long was the fish?</string>
    <string name="Q97">It takes 3 parts of cement and 4 parts of sand to make a specific mixture.\n\nHow many containers of cement are required, to make of 28 containers of mixture?</string>
    <string name="Q98">In a chemistry lab, they are facing a problem.\n\nHow many liters of a 20 percent solution should be added to 40 liters of 80 percent solution, to make a mixture containing 50 percent of concentration?</string>
    <string name="Q99">Little Mary has a great passion for candies and even a greater passion for math.\n\nToday she decided to share her box of candies with her friends.\nShe places her friends in a row and then distributes the candies.\nShe gives two candies to the first kid in line, then three to the second, five to the third, seven to the fourth and eleven to the fifth.\n\nHow many candies will be getting the seventh kid in line?</string>
    <string name="Q100">During the war, general Walsh intercepts an ennemy message.\nThe message says:\n\n\'EM EQTT IBBIKS BWUWZZWE\'\n\nWould you be able to decipher the coded transmission?</string>
    <string name="Q101">After a wild party, a Mike falls asleep at 6.00 A.M.\n\nWhen he wakes up he asks \'What time is it? How long have I been sleeping?\'\n\nHis room mate answers: \'If it were two hours later it would be half as long until midnight as it would be if it were an hour later.\'\n\nCan you help Mike discover has long he\' been asleep?</string>

</resources>